回归大局
returning to the big picture
如果 kickstarter 或
what happens if either the kickstarter or
提供其进程的服务是崩溃的
services to provide their process is crash
谁来监督主管
who's going to supervise the supervisors
井监督员可以监督生成服务器和
well supervisors can supervise both gen servers and
其他主管
other supervisors
因为主管
because the supervisor
本身就是一种特殊的gen server
itself is a special type of gen server
所以我们将添加一个顶级主管
so we'll add a top level supervisor
简单地命名为主管
simply named supervisor
从而创建一个监督树
and thereby create a supervision tree
分层嵌套主管的结果，如
an upshot of nesting supervisors hierarchically like
这是如果工作进程崩溃
this is if a worker process crashes
它的退出信号
its exit signal
不会传播到其直接主管之外
doesn't propagate beyond its immediate supervisor
记住每个主管都以这种方式捕获退出信号
remember each supervisor traps exit signals in this way
运行时空气被隔离到特定的子树
runtime airs are isolated to a specific sub tree
应用程序的其余部分一直在嗡嗡作响
and the rest of the application keeps humming along
让我们创建顶级主管
let's create the top level supervisor
它只会被称为主管得到yx
it's just going to be called supervisor got yx
和调查主管
and survey supervisor
再一次，这个命名没有什么魔力
and again there's no magic to this naming
这只是我们的顶级主管
this is just our top level supervisor
我们称它为主管
we call it supervisor
你可以称之为顶级主管
you could call it top level supervisor
或任何对你有意义的东西
or whatever makes sense to you
关键是你使用了这种主管行为
the key thing is that you use this supervisor behavior
现在我们需要一个开始链接和一个
now we're going to need a start link and an
nit功能非常
nit function very
类似于我们的服务主管中已有的内容
similar to what's already in our services supervisor
所以我要继续复制那些
so I'm just going to go ahead and copy those over
我们的高层主管又来了
there's our top level supervisor again
我会把它们粘贴进去
and I'll paste those in
然后我们就改变
and then we'll just change
这从启动服务主管到启动
this from starting the service supervisor to starting
主管
the supervisor
然后就孩子而言，这将是
and then in terms of the children it's going to be
服务启动器
servy kickstarter
那是一个 gen 服务器，然后是
that's a gen server and then the
第二个将是
second one is going to be
服务主管
servy services supervisor
这是我们的二级主管
which is our 2nd level supervisor
我们将再次使用它
and again we're going to use this
一对一重启策略
one for one restart strategy
如果你想让它重新启动一切
if you wanted it to restart everything
如果其中一个孩子撞车，您可以使用一个
if either of the children crash you could use one
对所有人
for all
但我们要一对一使用
but we're going to use one for one
请记住，树中的每个主管
just keep in mind that each supervisor in the tree
可以使用不同的重启策略
can use a different restart strategy
视情况而定
depending on the situation
就像我们以前做的那样
as we did before
为了这个工作
for this to work
我们需要做
we need to make
对 kickstarter 和
minor changes to both kickstarter and
服务主管所以
services supervisors so
他们遵守约定
that they follow the conventions
所以我们将从kickstarter开始
so we'll start with kickstarter
我们将从头开始重命名接口函数
we'll rename the interface function from start
开始链接
to start link
当我们启动 gen 服务器时，我们需要调用 start
and when we start the gen server we need to call start
链接以及然后记住
link as well and then remember
主管将通过一个 arg
the supervisor is going to pass an arg
这将忽略
which will ignore
把它存起来
save that away
然后在我们的服务主管那里
then over in our services supervisor which is the
另一个孩子
other child
好吧，我们已经找到了一个惊人的功能
well we already have a startling function to find
但它需要一个将忽略的 arg
but it needs to take an arg which will ignore
做出这些改变
with those changes made
我们准备启动顶级主管
we're ready to fire up the top level supervisor
好吧，它将成为主管 pid
so okay and it's going to be the supervisor pid
我们打电话给调查主管开始链接
we call survey supervisor start link
很棒的启动
awesome that starts up
一切为了我们
everything for us
现在我们知道它是如何开始它的孩子的
now we know how it started its children
是的，因为 kickstarter 是一个 gem 服务器
yeah since kickstarter is a gem server
它有一个子规格功能
it has a child spec function
所以调查kickstarter
so survey kickstarter
它称为子规范函数
it called the child spec function
传递给它一个空列表
passed it an empty list
并返回其子规范
and that returns its child spec
请注意该功能已启动
notice that the function is start
链接并传入
link and it passes in
一个空列表，我们有一个开始链接功能，所以
a empty list and we've got a start link function so
它只是叫它
it just called it
有趣的是
and interestingly
即使服务主管是主管
even though services supervisor is a supervisor
它还有一个子规格
it also has a child spec
所以如果我们看一下服务主管
so if we look at services supervisor
调用它的子规范函数
call its child spec function
看看那个
well look at that
它有一张看起来与kickstarter非常相似的地图
it's got a map that looks very similar to kickstarter
唯一的区别是
only difference is
你知道这是服务主管
you know it's services supervisor
它要开始了
it's going to start
通过调用启动链接服务主管
services supervisor by calling start link
在一个空列表中
in an empty list
你注意到这种情况下的类型是主管
and you notice the type in this case is supervisor
而不是工人
rather than worker
所以当你使用主管行为时
so when you use the supervisor behavior
默认
a default
子规范函数被自动注入
child spec function is automatically injected
进入具有默认主管类型的模块
into the module which has a default type of supervisor
基本上它只是儿童规格
basically it's just child specs all the way down
现在如果我们的网络服务器进程崩溃了
now if our web server process crashes
它应该重新启动
it should get restarted
不影响应用程序的其余部分
without affecting the rest of the application
我们去找吧
let's go find it
每个 itupee 服务器
each itupee server
将它通过管道进入进程出口
will pipe it into process exit
我们会寄给它caboom
and we'll send it caboom
完善 kickstarter
perfect the kickstarter
捕获退出信号并重新启动 Web 服务器
trapped the exit signal and restarted the web server
但其他进程不受影响
but the other processes weren't impacted
让我们尝试让质押服务器崩溃
let's try crashing the pledge server
由二级主管管理
which is managed by the second level supervisor
好的，在这种情况下，二级服务主管
okay in this case the second level services supervisor
困住了退出信号
trapped the exit signal which
触发了子进程的重启
triggered a restart of the child process
我们在这里看到
we see that right here
它
and it
也阻止了退出信号的传播
also prevented the exit signal from being propagated
再往上走
further up the tree
再次如此
so again
箭头被隔离到这个主管子树
the arrow was isolated to this supervisor sub tree
所以现在让我们崩溃服务主管本身
so now let's crash the services supervisor itself
我就这样搞定
I'm just going to get it this way
进程在哪里
process where is
我们用这个名字注册了这个
and we registered this under the name
这是它的模块，所以它的
which was its module so its
服务主管
services supervisor
那是pid
that's the pid
然后我们可以在该pid上调用进程退出
and then we can call process exit on that pid
并使supervisor异常终止
and to make the supervisor terminate abnormally
我们不能只发送 caboom
we can't just send it caboom
我们不能给它发送任何类似的旧理由
we can't send it any old reason like that
主管将捕获退出信号
the supervisor will trap exit signals
但是 kill 是一个无法捕捉的退出信号
but kill is an untrappable exit signal
所以我们会通过它杀死
so we're gonna pass it kill
听起来很残酷
it sounds pretty brutal
但这就是我们需要做的让主管崩溃
but that's what we need to do to crash a supervisor
我们看到它重新启动
and we see that it gets restarted
它也开始了它的孩子
and it also started its children
那么为什么它必须重新启动它的孩子
so why did it have to restart its children
在终止服务主管时
while terminating the services supervisor
导致其所有孩子被终止
caused all of its children to be terminated
因为记得
because remember
链接是定向的
links are by directional
这实际上是一件好事
this is actually a good thing
你可以终止主管
you can terminate a supervisor
不用担心自己的孩子会成为孤儿
without worrying about its children being orphaned
在无人监督的情况下到处乱跑
and running around unsupervised
所以现在你明白长生不老药
so now you understand how elixir
骑在耳朗 vm 上
riding atop the earlang vm
并利用 otp 库
and leveraging otp libraries
很好
is well
适用于需要高可用性的系统和
suited for systems that require high availability and
容错
fault tolerance
这是非常了不起的东西，记住
it's pretty amazing stuff and remember
它经过了多次实战考验
it's been battle tested through many
生产使用年限
years of production use